<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bhutan on Travel</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/tags/bhutan/</link><description>Recent content in Bhutan on Travel</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/tags/bhutan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Punakha Adventures: Rivers, Rafting, and Ancient Fortresses</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/punakha-personal-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/punakha-personal-experience/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="from-thimphu-to-the-warm-valley"&gt;From Thimphu to the Warm Valley&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive from Thimphu to Punakha was like traveling through different seasons in a single day. We climbed up to Dochula Pass with its 108 memorial chortens, then descended into the warm, subtropical Punakha valley. The temperature change was dramatic - from needing jackets to feeling the warm valley breeze.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Thimphu Experience: Night Streets and Karaoke Culture</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/thimphu-personal-experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/thimphu-personal-experience/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="arriving-in-a-capital-unlike-any-other"&gt;Arriving in a Capital Unlike Any Other&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the winding mountain drive from Phuentsholing, arriving in Thimphu felt like entering a different world. This is the only capital city I&amp;rsquo;ve been to without a single traffic light - instead, a policeman in traditional dress gracefully directs traffic with hand gestures. It perfectly captures what makes Thimphu special: progress on its own terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Bhutan Journey: 8 Days in the Land of Thunder Dragon</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/bhutan-journey-siliguri-to-paro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/bhutan-journey-siliguri-to-paro/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-journey-that-changed-my-perspective"&gt;The Journey That Changed My Perspective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What started as a simple plan to visit Bhutan turned into one of the most transformative travel experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had. Over 10 days, I journeyed from Gurgaon to Siliguri, then crossed into the serene monasteries of Paro, discovering a country that truly lives by different values.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>