<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travelogue on Travel</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/categories/travelogue/</link><description>Recent content in Travelogue on Travel</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/categories/travelogue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Punakha: Where the Rivers Whisper and Time Stands Still</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/destinations/bhutan/punakha-the-heart-of-bhutan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/destinations/bhutan/punakha-the-heart-of-bhutan/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-descent-into-silence"&gt;The Descent into Silence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Thimphu is the pulse of Bhutan, Punakha is its soul. The drive from the capital felt like a descent into a deeper, more ancient peace. For me, this was the highlight of the trip—the most silent, serene city I have ever encountered. Punakha doesn&amp;rsquo;t demand your attention; it simply exists in a state of grace, wrapped in the arms of the mountains and the constant, rhythmic song of its rivers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thimphu: The Capital of Stillness and Painted Wood</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/destinations/bhutan/thimphu-travelogue-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 18:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/destinations/bhutan/thimphu-travelogue-experience/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-road-finally-begins"&gt;The Road Finally Begins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving the border felt like shedding a skin. Until now, the journey had been a long sequence of transits—the rush of Gurgaon, the rhythm of the Rajdhani to Siliguri, and the crossing at Phuentsholing. But as our &lt;strong&gt;Coaster Bus&lt;/strong&gt; began to tilt into the first few mountain bends toward Thimphu, it finally hit me: the trip has truly started.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Udaipur: A Whirlwind Romance with the City of Lakes</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/destinations/udaipur/udaipur-city-of-lakes-romance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 11:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/destinations/udaipur/udaipur-city-of-lakes-romance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d always heard whispers of Udaipur&amp;rsquo;s charm, the &amp;ldquo;Venice of the East,&amp;rdquo; a city painted in hues of royal blue and gold. But nothing prepared me for the moment I first saw it. After a scenic six-hour train ride from Jaipur, the city unfolded before me, a breathtaking panorama of majestic palaces and serene lakes that seemed to shimmer with a thousand stories. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a trip; it was the beginning of a whirlwind romance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>