<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Travel</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Travel</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:05:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dharamshala - McLeod Ganj - Palampur - Kareri Complete Itinerary</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/dharamshala-mcleod-ganj-palampur-kareri-complete-itinerary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:05:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/dharamshala-mcleod-ganj-palampur-kareri-complete-itinerary/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/images/dharmshala/dharamshala-hero.jpg" alt="Dharamshala mountain view"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The serene beauty of Dharamshala nestled in the Dhauladhar mountains&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Escape the Delhi NCR chaos and immerse yourself in the spiritual and natural beauty of Dharamshala, the Dalai Lama&amp;rsquo;s residence and gateway to incredible Himalayan adventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kuari Pass - Chopta - Tungnath - Chandrashila Trek</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/kuari-pass-chopta-tungnath-chandrashila-trek/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/kuari-pass-chopta-tungnath-chandrashila-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Experience the legendary &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lord Curzon Trail&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; and visit the world&amp;rsquo;s highest Shiva temple in this incredible Himalayan adventure combining two spectacular treks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nainital Expedition 2024: A Journal of Lakes, Peaks, and Pahadi Thrills</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/nainital-expedition-2024-lakes-peaks-and-thrills/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 23:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/nainital-expedition-2024-lakes-peaks-and-thrills/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="part-1-pre-trip-reflections--logistics-the-before"&gt;Part 1: Pre-Trip Reflections &amp;amp; Logistics (The &amp;lsquo;Before&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="1-the-setup-escaping-may-heat-may-1st-night"&gt;1. The Setup: Escaping May Heat (May 1st Night)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &amp;lsquo;Why&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;: May 2024 meant one thing in Delhi: heat. This Nainital trip was a necessity—a strategic retreat to the cool embrace of the Kumaon hills. The goal was simple: replace the city&amp;rsquo;s concrete buzz with mountain stillness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transportation Log&lt;/strong&gt;: The journey was anchored by the reliable &lt;strong&gt;Shatabdi Express (12039)&lt;/strong&gt; from Delhi, taking us straight to Kathgodam. Always a smooth ride, though arriving at night means missing the best parts of the travel scenery. A reliable choice for efficiency, though perhaps next time I&amp;rsquo;ll try an earlier train to catch the hills in daylight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2-arrival--the-steep-test-may-2nd-morning"&gt;2. Arrival &amp;amp; The Steep Test (May 2nd Morning)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arrival in Nainital&lt;/strong&gt;: From Kathgodam, we quickly organized a &lt;strong&gt;shared cab&lt;/strong&gt;—cost-effective and perfectly fine for the ascent. The air immediately felt crisp and clean, signaling the start of the holiday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accommodation Review: The Nest | Roof Top Suites&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: The property itself was excellent—great rooms, the promise of a bonfire/barbeque, and an unbeatable &lt;strong&gt;Naini Lake View&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip for Next Time&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Be warned about the climb!&lt;/strong&gt; Staying on Mall Road means sacrificing a flat walk. The &lt;strong&gt;250-300 meter walk&lt;/strong&gt; up to The Nest was &lt;em&gt;extremely steep&lt;/em&gt;. Great workout, terrible for tired legs after a long day. Worth the view, but factor in the daily &amp;lsquo;steep hike tax&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-2-daily-documentation-the-nainital-experience"&gt;Part 2: Daily Documentation (The &amp;lsquo;Nainital Experience&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="-day-1--2-lake-life-and-high-peaks-may-2nd--3rd"&gt;📅 Day 1 &amp;amp; 2: Lake Life and High Peaks (May 2nd &amp;amp; 3rd)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lake&amp;rsquo;s Core&lt;/strong&gt;: We spent quality time at &lt;strong&gt;Naini Lake&lt;/strong&gt;. The simple act of &lt;strong&gt;boating&lt;/strong&gt; on the crescent-shaped water remains the town&amp;rsquo;s heart. It&amp;rsquo;s calming, beautiful, and essential.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spiritual Stop&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;strong&gt;Naina Devi Temple&lt;/strong&gt; offered its beautiful location on the northern shore. It’s always bustling, but the view of the lake framed by the temple is a unique photo opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Steep Reward: Tiffin Top (Dorothy&amp;rsquo;s Seat)&lt;/strong&gt;: This was a required trek. The panoramic view of Nainital town nestled around the lake is simply stunning from here. A perfect spot to reflect and realize how perfectly the town is situated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Himalayan Glimpse: Snow View Point&lt;/strong&gt;: We accessed this via the &lt;strong&gt;cable car&lt;/strong&gt;—a great way to save energy and get a bird&amp;rsquo;s-eye view. The views of the snow-capped Himalayas (though maybe slightly hazy in May) were beautiful. A quick, fun activity, though the top itself can be crowded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market &amp;amp; Culture&lt;/strong&gt;: Exploring the &lt;strong&gt;Tibet Market&lt;/strong&gt; was a must. Perfect for souvenir hunting and soaking up the local energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="-culinary-discoveries-in-nainital"&gt;🍜 Culinary Discoveries in Nainital&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sakley&amp;rsquo;s Restaurant&lt;/strong&gt;: A must-visit bakery. Their reputation is well-earned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tibet Market Gems&lt;/strong&gt;: Found the famous &lt;strong&gt;Sonam Momos&lt;/strong&gt;—simple, steaming, and the accompanying chutney was spot on. A quick &lt;strong&gt;Chowmein&lt;/strong&gt; satisfied the street food craving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Taste&lt;/strong&gt;: Tried the local sweet, &lt;strong&gt;Bal Mithai&lt;/strong&gt;, and sampled a &lt;strong&gt;Pahadi Thali&lt;/strong&gt; for a genuine taste of the Kumaoni kitchen. Also, grabbing quick, hot food in the market near the Naina Temple provided a great, authentic vibe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-3-switching-bases--adventurous-rides-the-bhimtal-leg"&gt;Part 3: Switching Bases &amp;amp; Adventurous Rides (The &amp;lsquo;Bhimtal Leg&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="-day-3-tranquility-vs-thrill-may-4th-evening"&gt;🌳 Day 3: Tranquility vs. Thrill (May 4th Evening)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move to Bhimtal&lt;/strong&gt;: We checked into &lt;strong&gt;Country Inn Bhimtal&lt;/strong&gt;—a great change of pace, moving to the quieter &amp;lsquo;sister&amp;rsquo; lake town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lake Exploration&lt;/strong&gt;: Explored the nearby lakes. While Bhimtal itself is picturesque, &lt;strong&gt;Naukuchiatal&lt;/strong&gt; stood out as the best—serene, with its famous nine corners, offering a much calmer environment for reflection and walking than bustling Nainital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="-day-4-bike-baba-and-bliss-may-5th-morning"&gt;🏞️ Day 4: Bike, Baba, and Bliss (May 5th Morning)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ultimate Thrill: Mukteshwar Bike Ride&lt;/strong&gt;: This was the highlight adventure. Hiring a bike and riding to &lt;strong&gt;Mukteshwar&lt;/strong&gt; was incredibly thrilling. The winding roads, the dense oak and pine forests, and the sudden, expansive views made it an unforgettable journey. The air up there is pristine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Sacred Stop: Kainchi Dham&lt;/strong&gt;: On the way, we stopped at &lt;strong&gt;Shri Neem Karori Baba Ashram&lt;/strong&gt;. This place holds immense spiritual significance and is an oasis of calm. The setting, by the river, is beautiful and deeply peaceful—a must-visit for anyone seeking tranquility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Stop: Sat Tal&lt;/strong&gt;: We also drove to &lt;strong&gt;Sat Tal&lt;/strong&gt; in the evening. Its cluster of interconnected lakes surrounded by dense forest offered a wilder, more natural beauty. A perfect spot to watch the early evening light filter through the trees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="-culinary-notes-in-bhimtal"&gt;🍽️ Culinary Notes in Bhimtal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belpatra Cafe &amp;amp; Kitchen&lt;/strong&gt;: Found this spot near Bhimtal for some good dining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dakshin Express&lt;/strong&gt;: A specific find for a change of pace, offering South Indian flavors. A welcome break from the standard North Indian fare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-4-takeaways--future-planning-the-after"&gt;Part 4: Takeaways &amp;amp; Future Planning (The &amp;lsquo;After&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="-final-assessment--key-takeaways"&gt;💡 Final Assessment &amp;amp; Key Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Good&lt;/strong&gt;: The sheer thrill of the &lt;strong&gt;Mukteshwar bike ride&lt;/strong&gt; combined with the spiritual calm of &lt;strong&gt;Kainchi Dham&lt;/strong&gt; made Day 5 the absolute peak of the trip. The transition from the crowded charm of Nainital to the quiet serenity of Bhimtal was a perfect balance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;strong&gt;steep climb&lt;/strong&gt; to The Nest in Nainital was a daily physical tax. Also, Mall Road traffic, even in May, can be quite dense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget Recap&lt;/strong&gt;: (Self-Note: Need to calculate final figures, but the major expenditures were the Shatabdi tickets, two distinct accommodations, and the bike rental for the day trip.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="-notes-for-my-next-kumaon-trip"&gt;📝 Notes for My Next Kumaon Trip&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Must-Do Next Time&lt;/strong&gt;: While we saw a lot, I skipped the &lt;strong&gt;Eco Cave Gardens&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Hanuman Garhi&lt;/strong&gt;, and the colonial structures like &lt;strong&gt;Governor&amp;rsquo;s House/Raj Bhawan&lt;/strong&gt;. These should be prioritized for the next cultural immersion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to Skip&lt;/strong&gt;: I could likely shorten the time spent on the main Mall Road and instead dedicate more time to the deeper forest trails around Bhimtal/Naukuchiatal for true solitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential Gear&lt;/strong&gt;: Next time, remember that the altitude change between Nainital and Mukteshwar demands even &lt;strong&gt;warmer layers&lt;/strong&gt; for the bike ride. And definitely, &lt;strong&gt;sturdier shoes&lt;/strong&gt; for all those steep climbs!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Pink City to the Yoga Capital: A Soulful Journey Through Rishikesh and Haridwar</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/from-pink-city-to-the-yoga-capital-a-soulful-journey-through-rishikesh-and-haridwar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/from-pink-city-to-the-yoga-capital-a-soulful-journey-through-rishikesh-and-haridwar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="from-pink-city-to-the-yoga-capital-a-soulful-journey-through-rishikesh-and-haridwar"&gt;From Pink City to the Yoga Capital: A Soulful Journey Through Rishikesh and Haridwar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello fellow travellers! In October 2023, I embarked on an utterly exhilarating trip from the bustling streets of Jaipur to the tranquil banks of the Ganga in Rishikesh and Haridwar. It was a perfect blend of high-octane adventure and deep spiritual peace, all packed into six unforgettable days. Join me as I take you through this incredible journey through the heart of India&amp;rsquo;s spiritual capital.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unveiling the Secrets of Black Holes: A Journey into the Heart of Darkness</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/unveiling-the-secrets-of-black-holes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 22:11:36 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/unveiling-the-secrets-of-black-holes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast expanse of the cosmos, &lt;code&gt;there&lt;/code&gt; are few objects as mysterious and awe-inspiring as black holes. These enigmatic cosmic phenomena, once thought of as nothing more than theoretical curiosities, have now become a central focus of astronomical research. In this article, we embark on a journey deep into the heart of darkness, unraveling some of the secrets that lie within.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Udaipur - The City of Lakes: A Perfect 3-Day Royal Getaway</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/udaipur-the-city-of-lakes-a-perfect-3-day-royal-getaway/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/udaipur-the-city-of-lakes-a-perfect-3-day-royal-getaway/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/images/udaipur/udaipur-hero.jpg" alt="Udaipur City Palace and Lake Pichola"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The magnificent City Palace overlooking the pristine waters of Lake Pichola&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discover the enchanting &amp;ldquo;City of Lakes&amp;rdquo; where royal heritage meets natural beauty. From grand palaces to serene boat rides, Udaipur offers a perfect blend of history, culture, and scenic splendor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Galactic Marvels: The Most Spectacular Nebulas in the Cosmos</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/galactic-marvels/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 11:15:17 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/galactic-marvels/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast expanse of the cosmos, one cannot help but be captivated by the breathtaking beauty of nebulae. These celestial marvels are often hidden in the depths of space, waiting to be discovered and admired by astronomers and space enthusiasts alike. In this article, we will embark on a cosmic journey to explore some of the most spectacular nebulas in the cosmos, shedding light on their unique features and the mysteries they hold.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stellar Spectacles: The Wonders of Supernova Explosions</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/stellar-spectacles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 22:45:37 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/stellar-spectacles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast expanse of the cosmos, few events match the spectacle and scientific importance of supernova explosions. These awe-inspiring cosmic fireworks mark the dramatic end of a star&amp;rsquo;s life and offer profound insights into the universe&amp;rsquo;s workings. In this article, we embark on a journey to explore the wonders of supernova explosions, shedding light on their significance and the mysteries they unveil.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Space Exploration's Next Frontier: The Race to Reach Mars</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/space-explorations-next-frontier/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 13:45:49 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/space-explorations-next-frontier/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The dream of reaching Mars has captured the imagination of scientists, engineers, and space enthusiasts for decades. In recent years, this dream has transformed into a tangible goal, with various space agencies and private companies embarking on missions to make it a reality. In this article, we delve into space exploration&amp;rsquo;s next frontier—the race to reach Mars.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Great Beyond: Exploring the Expanding Universe</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/the-great-beyond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 14:15:05 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2023/the-great-beyond/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The universe, with its vastness and complexity, has intrigued humanity for centuries. In recent decades, our understanding of the cosmos has deepened, thanks to groundbreaking discoveries about the expansion of the universe. In this article, we embark on a journey to explore the great beyond, delving into the universe&amp;rsquo;s expansion and the mysteries it unveils.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cosmic Time Travel: Peering into the Universe's Past with Telescopes</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2022/cosmic-time-travel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:30:32 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2022/cosmic-time-travel/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the realm of astronomy, telescopes are our time machines, allowing us to peer into the distant past of the universe. These remarkable instruments have the power to capture light that has traveled across the cosmos for millions or even billions of years. In this article, we embark on a journey of cosmic time travel, exploring how telescopes enable us to witness the universe&amp;rsquo;s history.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Hubble Space Telescope: 30 Years of Stunning Discoveries</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2022/the-hubble-space-telescope/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 09:30:32 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2022/the-hubble-space-telescope/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For three remarkable decades, the Hubble Space Telescope has been our eye on the universe, delivering breathtaking images and transformative scientific insights. Since its launch in 1990, the Hubble has reshaped our understanding of the cosmos and provided us with unparalleled views of distant galaxies, nebulae, and other celestial wonders. In this article, we celebrate the Hubble Space Telescope&amp;rsquo;s 30 years of stunning discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exoplanets: Hunting for Earth's Cosmic Cousins</title><link>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2022/exoplanets-hunting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 13:03:07 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://aakashkh.github.io/travel/posts/2022/exoplanets-hunting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast tapestry of the cosmos, one of the most intriguing quests of modern astronomy is the search for exoplanets, distant celestial bodies that might bear a resemblance to our own Earth. This endeavor is driven by the tantalizing question: Could there be other habitable worlds out there? In this article, we embark on a journey to explore the captivating hunt for Earth&amp;rsquo;s cosmic cousins.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>